<chapter id="sum.introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.scope">
        <title>Scope</title>
        <para>This document is the software user manual (SUM) for the MERIS Glint processor.</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.objectives">
        <title>Objectives</title>
        <para>
            The scientific algorithms for glint correction have been implemented in a processor which is
            available as a plugin for the BEAM toolbox. This user manual gives a description of the
            software, i.e. how to install, how to use the graphical and command-line interfaces, and the
            input/output products of the processor.
        </para>
        <para>
            The GLINT processor basically consists of two main parts:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    FLINT: The algorithm to compute glint reflection at 865 nm from glint at SWIR and TIR
                    bands of AATSR
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    AGC: The atmosphere and glint correction algorithm
                </listitem>
			</itemizedlist>

            The FLINT computation is optional and provides a 'FLINT value' (the Glint reflection) as additional
            neural net input used by the AGC. The AGC can also be run standalone without FLINT input. The
            FLINT algorithm requires overlapping MERIS/AATSR L1b products as input, the AGC only needs
            a MERIS product.
        </para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.readerLevel">
        <title>Reader Level</title>
		
		<para>
			This specification is mainly written for the following audiences:
			<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
					BEAM Application users
				</listitem>
                <listitem>
					MERIS scientists
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>	
		</para>
		<para>
			This user manual specifications assume that the reader is familiar with basic concepts in
			using the BEAM software and its integrated processors.
		</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.acronymsAndNomenclature">
        <title>Acronyms and Nomenclature</title>
        <sect2 id="sum.introduction.acronyms">
            <title>Acronyms</title>
			
			<para>
				<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
					<listitem>
						BC - Brockmann Consult
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						ESA - European Space Agency
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						ESTEC -	European Space Technology and Research Centre
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						SUM - Software User Manual
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>	
			</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2 id="sum.introduction.nomenclature">
            <title>Nomenclature</title>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.referenceDocuments">
        <title>Reference Documents</title>
		
		<para>
			<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
                    [1] Preusker, R., and J. Fischer: Glint estimation in the NIR and SW infrared
                    bands of MERIS and AATSR using AATSR
                    measurements in the thermal infrared. FLINT ATBD, Version 0.9, 12 March 2009.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    [2] Doerffer, R.: Atmosphere and Glint Correction Project
                    Atmospheric and Glint Correction. AGC ATBD, Version 1.0, 01 September 2008.
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>
