<chapter id="sum.processor">
    <title>MERIS Glint Processor Interface</title>

    The GLINT processor graphical user interface(GUI) is invoked if the Tools menu entry 'Glint
    Correction (MERIS/(A)ATSR)...' is selected in Visat. The GLINT GUI is represented by one main
    dialog, which consists of the following main components:

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.io">
        <title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.iotab">
            <title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/iotab.png"/>
        </figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                Source product file (MERIS L1b): Select the MERIS input product file by either typing the product path
                into the text
                filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Checkbox 'Create FLINT product from AATSR L1b and use as AGC input': Select
                this checkbox if FLINT algorithm shall be processed.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Source product file (AATSR L1b): Select the AATSR input product file by either typing the product path
                into the text
                filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                This component is enabled only if checkbox 'Create FLINT product...' is selected, otherwise
                disabled.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Output product file: Select the Glint output product file by either typing the product path into the
                text
                filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Output product format and target directory:
                <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                    <listitem>
                        'Save as': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will be saved to disk.
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        Output product format: Select one of the available output product formats.
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        Select the output product directory by either typing the product path into the text
                        filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Open in Visat': If this checkbox is selected, the output product is opened in Visat
                after successful processing.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.procparameters">
        <title>'Processing Parameters' Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.ipftab">
            <title>'Processing Parameters' Tab Pane</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/procparamstab.png"/>
        </figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                'Perform SMILE correction': This checkbox enables or disables the SMILE correction.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Output TOSA reflectance': This checkbox toggles the output of TOSA reflectances.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Output normalization of bidirectional reflectances': This checkbox toggles the output of normalised
                bidirectional reflectances.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Output water leaving reflectance': This checkbox toggles the output of water leaving
                reflectances.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Output path reflectance': This checkbox toggles the output of path reflectances.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Output transmittance': This checkbox toggles the output of downwelling irradiance transmittance.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Derive water leaving reflectance from path reflectance': This checkbox switches between
                computation of water leaving reflectance from path reflectance and direct use of neural net
                output.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Land detection expression': The arithmetic expression used for land detection.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'MERIS net (leave empty to use default)': The file of the atmospheric net to be used instead
                of the default neural net in case of AGC-only computation.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                ’Use FLINT value in neural net (requires AATSR L1b source product)’:
                Toggles the usage of a FLINT value in AGC neural net. Note that this checkbox
                is purely informative and always disabled. It is automatically triggered by the checkbox
                'Create FLINT product...' in the I/O Parameters Tab Pane.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'FLINT net (leave empty to use default)': The file of the atmospheric net to be used instead
                of the default neural net in case of both FLINT and AGC computation.
                This component is enabled only if the checkbox 'Create FLINT product...'
                in the I/O Parameters Tab Pane has been selected, otherwise disabled.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.control">
        <title>Control Buttons</title>

        From all Glint Processor tab panes, the following control buttons can be accessed:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                'Run': If this button is clicked, the processor will start the computations.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Close': If this button is clicked, the Glint Processor dialog is closed.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Help': If this button is clicked, this manual is displayed as online help.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <figure id="figure.processor.controlbuttons">
            <title>Glint Processor control buttons</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/controlbuttons.png"/>
        </figure>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.gpt">
        <title>Processing from command line</title>

        Since the Glint Processor makes use of the BEAM graph processing framework, it can be
        used also as a command line tool outside BEAM-VISAT. The graph processing is invoked
        by the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        To obtain general help on the praph processing, use the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        Specific help on the MEPIX processor, can be obtained with
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h Meris.GlintCorrection
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        In this case, information on the usage and a list of all available parameters are given
        (see<xref linkend="figure.processor.gpt" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).


        <figure id="figure.processor.gpt">
            <title>Glint Processor command line processing</title>
            <graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/glint_gpt.png"/>
        </figure>

    </sect1>

</chapter>
